Guide to the Helen de Camp Gourlay Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Helen de Camp Gourlay papers
1913-1917
SC0694
Gourlay, Helen de Camp.
1 Linear feet
This collection contains course syllabi, notes, and exams from classes de Camp took at Pomona College, mostly philosophy and sociology, and at Stanford, primarily economics. Two of her Stanford courses were taught by Prof. Yamato Ichihashi (population and immigration). Other Stanford instructors were Margaret M. Lothrop (social agencies) and Wilfred Eldred (marketing).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Helen de Camp [Mrs. J. B. Gourlay] attended Stanford University during the 1916-17 school year, taking graduate classes in economics. She earned her a.b. at Pomona College in 1915.
Description of the Collection
This collection contains course syllabi, notes, and exams from classes de Camp took at Pomona College, mostly philosophy and sociology, and at Stanford, primarily economics. Two of her Stanford courses were taught by Prof. Yamato Ichihashi (population and immigration). Other Stanford instructors were Margaret M. Lothrop (social agencies) and Wilfred Eldred (marketing).
Access Terms
Eldred, Wilfred, 1888?-1978.; Gourlay, Helen de Camp.; Ichihashi, Yamato; Lothrop, Margaret Mulford, 1884-; Pomona College (Claremont, Calif.)--Students.; Economics--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Pomona College papers
  - "The Debt of the Public School to the Backward Child", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Philosophy of Loyalty--Josiah Royce", circa 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Plato's Idea of the Good", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Social Settlement Teaching", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Book reviews, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Assorted notes (mostly on art and architecture) from Pomona College, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Applied Sociology--Economic and Social Societies, notes, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "God, Freedom and Immortality--Immanuel Kant", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Hebrews in their old Houses. The second report.", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Jewish Immigrant", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Utilitarianism by John Stuart Mill", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy C25 class at Pomona, exam (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Psychology, city problems, notes, no date (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Class notes, assorted, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Stanford University papers
  - Economics 63b, History of Economic Thought in the U.S., syllabus (from the 1915-16 year) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Economics 2, Political Science, syllabus and notes, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Economics 2, Political Science, paper and exams, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Political Science notes, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Economics 53, Population, syllabus and notes, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Economics 53, Population, exams, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Economics 53, Population, notes, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Economics 23, Social Agencies, syllabus and notes, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Economics 23, Social Agencies, paper and exam, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Economics 23, Social Agencies, readings, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Economics 25, Marketing, syllabus and notes, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Economics 25, Marketing, exams, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Education 24, Adolescence, syllabus and notes, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Economics 54, Immigration and the Race Problem, syllabus and notes, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Economics 54, Immigration and the Race Problem, exams, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Notes, possibly from immigration class, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Notes (societal evolution?), no date (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Notes, various, no date (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Essays (or possibly quizzes), no date (Box 2, Folder 20)